Greg Banks

Castleton-on-Hudson, NY 12033 | 631-671-5104 | gbanks1438@gmail.com GitHub | Linkedin | Medium

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Full stack Software Engineer that is currently a Communications Specialist for a smart home company. Collaborate with development and management teams to shape the voice of the brand. Create product Wikis from technical documents, write blogs, troubleshoot issues, and manage social media to engage with customers. Strong technical and communication skills allow me to be flexible in an ever changing industry.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Rails, SQL, Javascript, ActiveRecord, CSS, HTML, PostgreSQL, Heroku, React, and Wordpress.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Greg BnB - Github

An app for users to make reservations at three fictional vacation rentals and explore local activities.

- Utilized the 'bcrypt' Gem to enable authentication and salted password protection with validations.
- Applied client-side routing using React Router v6 for seamless component transitions.
- Created RESTful routes with CRUD operations to interact with the SQL database.
- Designed the MVC to ensure separation of concerns within the Ruby on Rails SPA.

Shopping App - Github

A simple shopping app with login functionality.

- Utilized the 'bcrypt' Gem for authentication to hash passwords with salt.
- Designed the back-end MVC and built it out with Ruby on Rails.
- Built the front-end using React Router v6 for dynamic client-side routing.
- Styling was finalized using vanilla HTML and CSS.

Lake House Vacation - Github - Frontend | Github - Backend

A simple app that explored the ability for users to make reservations at a fictional vacation lake house.

- Designed an API with Ruby and Sinatra, then used Active Record as an ORM for the back-end.
- Bootstrapped the front-end using Create React App and styled it using HTML and CSS.
- Set up component routing using React Router v6 to support the client.
- Used the 'sglite3' Gem to interact with the back-end database.

EXPERIENCE

Wink Labs Inc Schenectady, NY

Communications Specialist

SUNY Albany

09/2018 - Present

- Writing technical wikis about supported products, company blogs, and communications to users.
- Creating the voice of the brand for consistency in messaging.
- Helping teams collaborate on application verbiage.
- Engaging with social media to help inform customers and assist them with technical issues.

Support Technician 06/2015 - 09/2018

• Answering support tickets to assist users with technical issues and provide troubleshooting information.

EDUCATION

 Flatiron School Online

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

10/2021 - 02/2022

Albany, NY

12/2010